http://www.minizoo.org.uk/privacy-policy

Glasgow, Edinburgh, Dundee, Central Scotland call 07435753183
RSS
At Animal Man’s Mini Zoo we’re committed to protecting and respecting your privacy.
This Policy explains when and why we collect personal information about people who visit our website, how we use it, the conditions under which we may disclose it to others, and how we keep it secure.
We may change this Policy from time to time, so please check this page occasionally to ensure that you’re happy with any changes. You should also note that by using our website, you agree to be bound by this Policy.
Any questions regarding this Policy and our privacy practices should be sent by email to animalmansminizoo@gmail.com.
Or by writing to:
Animal Man’s Mini Zoo
40 Westbourne Gardens
Glasgow
Alternatively, you can telephone 0141 237 6164.
How do we collect information from you?
We obtain information about you when you use our website, for example, when you complete the contact form, when you finish the site registration form, purchase a product from our store or engage with other contact forms within our site.
What type of information do we collect from you?
The personal information we collect might include your name, address, email address, IP address, and information regarding what pages are accessed and when. If you make a donation online or purchase a product from us, your card information is not held by us; it is collected by our third-party payment processors who specialise in the secure online capture and processing of credit/debit card transactions, as explained below.
Use of ‘cookies’
Like many other websites, the Animal Man’s Mini Zoo website uses cookies. ‘Cookies’ are small pieces of information sent by an organisation to your computer and stored on your hard drive to allow that website to recognise you when you visit. They collect statistical data about your browsing actions and patterns and do not identify you as an individual. For example, we use cookies to store your store preference. And this information helps us to improve our website and deliver a better more personalised service.
It is possible to switch off cookies by setting your browser preferences. For more information on how to switch off cookies on your computer, visit our full cookies policy. However, turning cookies off may result in a loss of functionality when using our website.
The main cookies used on our site:
Google Analytics
These cookies are used to collect information about how visitors use our site. We use the information to compile reports and to help us improve the site.
The cookies collect information in an anonymous form, including the number of visitors to the site, where visitors have come to the website from and the pages they visited.
For more information on Google Analytic’s privacy policy visit here – http://www.google.com/analytics/learn/privacy.html
Google Maps
These are Google Maps third-party cookies, which are unique identifiers to allow traffic analysis to Google Maps.
How is your information used?
We may use your information to:
Contact you regarding queries raised in the contact form;
Progress an order you have submitted and sent you information directly related to this;
Process a donation that you have made;
Carry out our obligations arising from any contracts entered into between us;
Seek your views or comments on the services we provide;
Notify you of changes to our services;
Send you communications which you have requested, and that may be of interest to you.
These may include information about campaigns, appeals, other fundraising activities, promotions of our associated companies goods and services.
Process a job application.
We review our retention periods for personal information on a regular basis. We are legally required to keep some types of information to fulfil our statutory obligations. We will hold your personal information on our systems for as long as is necessary for the relevant activity, or as long as is set out in any suitable contract, you hold with us.
Who has access to your information?
We will not sell or rent your information to third parties.
We will not share your information with third parties for marketing purposes.
When you are using our secure store pages, your payments are processed by a third party payment processor, who specialises in the safe online capture and processing of credit/debit card transactions. If you have any questions regarding secure sales, please contact us.
We may transfer your personal information to a third party as part of a sale of some or all of our business and assets to any third party or as part of any business restructuring or reorganisation. Or we may transfer your information if we’re under a duty to disclose or share your data to comply with any legal obligation or to enforce or apply our terms of use or to protect the rights, property or safety of our supporters and customers. However, we will take steps with the aim of ensuring that we continue to protect your privacy rights.
Your Choices
You have a choice about whether or not you wish to receive information from us. If you do not want to receive direct marketing communications from us about our exciting products and services, then you can select your choices by ticking the relevant boxes situated on the form on which we collect your information.
We will not contact you for marketing purposes by email unless you have given your prior consent.
You can change your marketing preferences at any time by completing the opt-out form here:
Click here to opt-out.
How you can access and update your information
The accuracy of your information is important to us. You have the right to request a copy of the report we hold about you so that you can ensure its accuracy. You can do this by the following methods.
Send an email to animalmansminizoo@gmail.com here and request the information held about you:
Any questions regarding this Policy and our privacy practices should be sent by email to animalmansminizoo@gmail.com.
Or by writing to:
Animal Man’s Mini Zoo
40 Westbourne Gardens
Glasgow
Alternatively, you can telephone 0141 237 6164.
Right to erasure
Visitors/users of the site should have the ability to have all records of their data held by a business where there is no legitimate reason for that business to maintain that reason; this includes where GDPR is super-ceded by other laws governing the details obtained.
Security precautions in place to protect the loss, misuse or alteration of your information
When you give us personal information, we take steps to ensure we treat it securely. Any sensitive information (such as credit or debit card details) is encrypted and protected with the following software 128 Bit encryption on SSL. When you are on a secure page, a lock icon will appear on the bottom of web browsers such as Microsoft Internet Explorer.
As non-sensitive details (your email address etc.) are transmitted over the Internet, they can never be guaranteed to be 100% secure. As a result, while we strive to protect your personal information, we cannot ensure the security of any information you send to us, and you do so at your own risk. Once we receive your information, we make our best effort to ensure its security on our systems. Where we have given (or where you have chosen) a password which enables you to access certain parts of our websites, you are responsible for keeping this password confidential. We ask you not to share your password with anyone.
Profiling
We may analyse your personal information to create a profile of your interests and preferences so that we can contact you with information relevant to you. We may make use of additional information about you when it is available from external sources to help us do this effectively. We may also use your personal information to detect and reduce fraud and credit risk.
Links to other websites
Our website may contain links to other sites run by other organisations. This privacy policy applies only to our website, so we encourage you to read the privacy statements on the other websites you visit. We cannot be responsible for the privacy policies and practices of other sites even if you access them using links from our website.
Also, if you linked to our website from a third party site, we cannot be responsible for the privacy policies and practices of the owners and operators of that third party site and recommend that you check the policy of that third party site.
16 or under
We are concerned to protect the privacy of children aged 16 or younger. If you are aged 16 or under, please get your parent/guardian’s permission beforehand whenever you provide us with personal information.
Transferring your information outside of Europe
As part of the services offered to you through this website, the information that you provide to us may be transferred to countries outside the European Union (“EU”). By way of example, this may happen if any of our servers are from time to time located in a country outside of the EU. These countries may not have similar data protection laws to the UK. By submitting your data, you agree to this transfer, storing or processing. If we transfer your information outside of the EU in this way, we will take steps to ensure that appropriate security measures are made with the aim of making sure that your privacy rights continue to be protected as outlined in this Policy.
If you use our services while you are outside the EU, your information may be transferred outside the EU to provide you with those services.
Review of this Policy
We keep this Policy under regular review. This Policy was last updated in April 2018.
Opt Out Form
Please leave this field empty.
I no longer want you to store my data.
